<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>YottaDB on FOSDEM 2021 Stands</title><link>https://stands.fosdem.org/stands/yottadb/</link><description>Recent content in YottaDB on FOSDEM 2021 Stands</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://stands.fosdem.org/stands/yottadb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ACID Properties</title><link>https://stands.fosdem.org/stands/yottadb/acid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stands.fosdem.org/stands/yottadb/acid/</guid><description>ACID Properties YottaDB implements transactions with strong Atomic, Consistent, Isolated, Durable (ACID) properties. Consider application logic to move $100 from a savings account to a checking account, which conceptually consists of the following steps:
Validate that the accounts exist, that the requested transfer is permitted, that there is sufficient balance, that the transfer request is authenticated, etc. Subtract $100 from the savings account. Add $100 to the checking account. Compute and debit any applicable service charges.</description></item><item><title>Business Continuity</title><link>https://stands.fosdem.org/stands/yottadb/business_continuity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stands.fosdem.org/stands/yottadb/business_continuity/</guid><description>Business Continuity While Durability is based on recovering application state from persistent non-volatile storage, business continuity of an application requires recovery of application state even in the face of loss of that non-volatile storage, e.g., the unplanned loss of a data center or a geography. In the event of unplanned loss of a data center or a geography, a mission critical application should continue to be available from another data center.</description></item><item><title>Features</title><link>https://stands.fosdem.org/stands/yottadb/features/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stands.fosdem.org/stands/yottadb/features/</guid><description>Features Multi-Language Database Access While the historic roots of YottaDB are in the M language, YottaDB extends the tight integration of the language with the database to other languages. As C is the lingua franca of programming languages (in that all programming languages have the ability to call a C API), YottaDB’s C language API extends the database engine to all programming languages. Through the C API, bindings (called &amp;ldquo;wrappers&amp;rdquo;) exist to natively access YottaDB concurrently also from Go, Perl, and Rust.</description></item><item><title>Hello World Examples</title><link>https://stands.fosdem.org/stands/yottadb/hello_world/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stands.fosdem.org/stands/yottadb/hello_world/</guid><description>The following sections discuss YottaDB&amp;rsquo;s Multi-Language support via a simple sayHello example. Each language uses its own sample program to add a node in the same database. Then the MUPIP EXTRACT command is used to display the contents of that database, successfully showing YottaDB being accessed by different languages.
Access from C YottaDB comes with a C API and all you need to use it is the gcc compiler. The sayhelloC.</description></item><item><title>How It Works</title><link>https://stands.fosdem.org/stands/yottadb/how_it_works/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stands.fosdem.org/stands/yottadb/how_it_works/</guid><description>How It Works Data Structure: Key-Value Tuples The fundamental core data structure provided by YottaDB is key-value tuples.
Following is a set of key-value tuples:
[&amp;quot;Capital&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;Belgium&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;Brussels&amp;quot;] [&amp;quot;Capital&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;Thailand&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;Bangkok&amp;quot;] [&amp;quot;Capital&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;USA&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;Washington, DC&amp;quot;] Each of the above tuples is called a node. In an n-tuple, the first n-1 items are keys, and the last item is the value associated with the keys. Data in YottaDB is always ordered according to the keys.
YottaDB itself assigns no meaning to the data in each node.</description></item><item><title>In-Memory Engine</title><link>https://stands.fosdem.org/stands/yottadb/in_memory_engine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stands.fosdem.org/stands/yottadb/in_memory_engine/</guid><description>In-Memory Engine At the core of YottaDB is a daemon-less key-value database engine that executes within the address space of the application process, which makes in-memory calls to a YottaDB API. Combining the database engine and application logic in a single process yields several benefits:
Robustness A simpler architecture means that in the event of abnormal process termination or other process failure, the other processes of the application can continue. With a daemon, failure of a daemon process stalls the operation of multiple processes and perhaps even multiple applications.</description></item><item><title>Optimistic Concurrency Control</title><link>https://stands.fosdem.org/stands/yottadb/occ/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stands.fosdem.org/stands/yottadb/occ/</guid><description>Optimistic Concurrency Control Unlike most high-end transactional database engines, YottaDB uses Optimistic Concurrency Control (OCC) to implement ACID transactions. Since transactions do not typically collide, optimistic techniques scale up better than other techniques. OCC and the daemon-less architecture reinforce each other to provide the extreme level of scalability that YottaDB users have come to expect.
How YottaDB OCC Works Every database records a transaction number in its file header. Each database block header records the database transaction number when that block was last updated.</description></item><item><title>Success Stories</title><link>https://stands.fosdem.org/stands/yottadb/success_stories/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stands.fosdem.org/stands/yottadb/success_stories/</guid><description>Success Stories University of Antwerp Library YottaDB powers The University of Antwerp Library catalog, which includes 3.7 million copies of 2.4 million titles, and delivers fast response times and reliable access to users around the world.
Government Savings Bank With 60 million accounts today, Government Savings Bank is one the largest financial institutions in Thailand, and a third of all Thais have an account at GSB.</description></item><item><title>Use Cases</title><link>https://stands.fosdem.org/stands/yottadb/use_cases/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stands.fosdem.org/stands/yottadb/use_cases/</guid><description>Use Cases Transactional Systems A real-time transaction processing system is one that records in a database the change in state of an entity as it happens (instead of, for example, capturing changes of state on paper or other means, then processing the data in a &amp;ldquo;batch&amp;rdquo; process). A change in the state may be registering a patient at the hospital, recording an empty parking space as occupied, transferring money from one account to another, shipping a widget from a warehouse, etc.</description></item></channel></rss>